Quentin P. Gore Papers
Quentin P. Gore Papers
1927-1967
Gore, Quentin P.
3.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American journalist, editor at the Chicago Sun-Times. Correspondence (1927-1967); photographs; manuals and other material pertaining to typography and printing; and a scrapbook of Gore's columns The axis on the air (1944-1946).
149016
Biographical History
Quentin P. Gore was an American journalist and editor of the Chicago Sun-Times. He was also the author of The Chicago Sun-Times type and makeup manual. (1964)
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Quentin P. Gore Papers comprise four series. Miscellaneous contains a movie editing kit. Published material contains books pertaining to newspaper publishing as well as issues of Linotype News, a magazine for those in the printing field. Subject files contains mainly correspondence about the Chicago Sun-Times, a newspaper edited by Gore. Writings contains volumes of Gore's Typographical and makeup manual as well as a scrapbook of clippings of his column, "The Axis on the Air."
Arrangement
Each series is arranged alphabetically by type (Published material), topic (Subject files), or title (Writings).
Related Material
has made a concerted effort over the years to ensure that its manuscript and rare books holdings complement each other. As a result, many of our manuscript collections are supported by books, pamphlets, serials and other items which are cataloged in the Rare Books Collection. Please be sure to search for these related materials.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Publishing, printing and book arts; Gore, Quentin P. Archives.; Chicago sun-times.; Journalists -- United States.; Newspaper editors -- United States.; Newspapers, Sections, columns, etc.; Makeup (Printing); Printing -- Style manuals.; Correspondence.; Newspaper columns.; Scrapbooks.; Journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Miscellaneous
  - Edit-ex movie editing kit (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Books (hardcover), 16 volumes (Box 1)
  - Books (softcover), 14 volumes (Box 2)
  - Booklets, 1940-1950 (Box 2)
  - Charts, loose papers (Box 2)
  - Linotype News, 1952-1962; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Subject files
  - Edmund Arnold, 1959-1965 (Box 2)
  - Codification of Makeup Rules and Practices, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
  - Gilbert Farrar, 1927-1957 (Box 2)
  - General, 1927-1967; undated; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Inland Daily Press Award, 1961-1963 (Box 2)
  - Marshall Field Award, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Photographs (Box 2)
  - Typographical manual, 1953-1965 (Box 2)
- Writings
  - Typographical and Makeup Manual, 10 volumes (Box 3)
  - Type and Makeup Manual, 4th edition, 2 copies (Oversize 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1944-1946 (Oversize 1)